Hello everyone.
I really request you to please give me five minutes to go over the syllabus together because once you're
going to go where this entire syllabus with me you're going to know that this is the perfect and best
course out there.
All right.
I have actually broken down my entire course in 10 different modules.
First module is about understanding Linux concept.
It will cover about Linux as Unix wars Linux.
And notice one thing every module I have I have included quizzes for you to do homework to do after
each module and handouts to read.
You don't really have to read each handout but it's good to have those resources in your hand.
Moving on to Module Two where we'll cover download install and configure actual linux machines or talk
about virtual machine downloading that motion machine.
We'll talk about what are the different ways to install Linux machine.
Then we'll cover the actual sent to US installation.
I have also included the optional Red Hat Linux installation lecture as well.
Then some somewhat on Linux desktop management on VM and then again ending with quizzes homework and
handouts.
Moving on to Module three which is about system access and file system and that is about command prompts
accessing Linux system downloading installed putty you need to know some important things about Linux.
I have covered that introduction to file system.
What are the different file system that are available then the basic command GDP WD and Alice.
That's where we gonna start.
Are Linux command lies moving onto a file system as you're going to see.
I'm going to skip them a very fast use review and go over it directly listing touch copy commands finding
files and write you wildcards offline Hertling quizzes homework and handouts.
Then module 4 is about Linux fundamentals commands syntax change mind.
This is all about permission to file permission.
Also ACL can access control which is a detail getting into the weeds getting help.
Tab completion adding text to the file pipes file management command.
Display command filters command compare files so many commands begin to learn in module 4 that is about
Linux fundamental and combining splitting files.
Linux vs. windows and of course quizzes homework and handout module 5 sys administration getting ever
more into the actual administration part.
We will talk about how we could VII A FILE difference between VM when it said it which is substitution
command.
We'll talk about use account management pseudo account.
How are you can manage your Linux users through active directory or to other at third party authentication.
We'll also talk about difference between LDN and that idea went by an open alt app then it will talk
about system utility commands always maintenance command changing system hostname finding system information
recovery password S.O.S reporter environment vary but a lot more I'm already getting out of breath and
we still on module 5 moving onto module 6 we'll talk about all about shell scripting I'll show you if
that's good for loose grips do was scripts and many scripts.
Module 7 networking servers and the system updates.
We'll talk about networking companies come bonding network ports downloading files from the Internet
as SSA sage works as a tell that we'll talk about DNS hostname and IP lookup A.P. crony d send mail
and all these services that you see.
I'm not just going to go where real quickly I'm actually going to work with you to go ahead and download
installing configure each of these servers then modulate is all about disk management all touched by
Ron levels we'll talk about disk partitions l VM is a biggest part of this where we're going to cover
everything about LV I'm adding disk removing disk we're going to talk about extending the existing partition
swap space raid file system check NF first complete big topic of an NFC compact I covered everything
from scratch also covered the difference between all redhead flavors module line OK.
Now up until modulate everything is covered on the technical side.
I'm not leaving you right here.
I'm actually holding your hand and taking the module line about how you should have your resume.
We'll have a resume or workshop cover letter.
Exposure to other technologies.
Homework handouts then module 10.
Just like resumé I am taking you to the next level where I'm going to tell you how you should be prepared
for your Linux interviews and that is something about Linux.
What is I.T. jobs that you have I.T. management when you apply for Linux job.
What do you need to expect.
Then interview vocab actual workshop then certification if you want to get into certification you want
to get a certification in Linux then we have 200 plus interview question that I'm going to give it to
you.
And of course homework and handouts and then of course recap.
This is not part of the module is just a recap what we have learned from this course and the final exam
is about question.
I really urge you to take that.
So you could you couldn't you know that you where you stand in this discourse then additional resources
I have to hunt 20 plus additional videos and lecture that you could take if you want to.
Now you decide now you be the judge.
Is this course are really going to make a difference in your life.
Well I'll tell you yes it will.
So please go ahead and click on unroll and you're going to find tons of resources in this course.
Good luck.